Christopher Moore collection of Indian Neck Folk Festival and other recordings
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 2: Sound recordings
  - Subseries 2: Coffeehouses and other venues
    - Solomon's Seal, reel #3, November 20, 1982, AFC 2016/055: SR154; RXK 4337; 1 sound tape reel (backcoated polyester, 00:46:52): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, stereo; 7 in.; About 00:07:49, Christopher Moore (as Chris Moore) is acknowledged as the person doing the sound for the performance, fro
      Scope and content: Continued from SR153. See the note for SR152.
    - "Twelfth Night," May 1968, AFC 2016/055: SR109; RXK 4292; 1 sound tape reel (polyester, 00:48:00): analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track; 7 in.
      Scope and content: Venue: Goddard College, in Plainfield, Vermont. A performance of the play "Twelfth Night," with rock music (some performances with vocals). See SR050. Original ID number: S-127.
    - Undergraduate Arts Festival, Ezra Stiles Concert. Part I: The New Folk Music - Dave Kaplan; Part II: Piano Recital - Allan Mallach (four tapes), February 27, 1964, AFC 2016/055: SR114; RXK 4297; 1 sound tape reel (polyester, 00:36:02): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, stereo; 7 in.; The parts of the concert in order: SR115 (second section), SR114, SR117, SR115 (first section), and SR118.
      Scope and content: Venue: Ezra Stiles College, Yale University. Dave Kaplan plays guitar and sings the following songs (among others): "It's A Hard Rain Gonna Fall," "Green, Green Rocky Road," and an unidentified song (first lines: "Well, I said to my baby, baby take it slow/I can't she said, I got to go"; "Lulu and Leonard"?). Original ID number: S-9.
    - Undergraduate Arts Festival, Ezra Stiles Concert. Part I: The New Folk Music - Dave Kaplan; Part II: Piano Recital - Allan Mallach (four tapes), February 27, 1964, AFC 2016/055: SR115; RXK 4298; 1 sound tape reel (polyester, 00:16:43): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, stereo; 7 in.; See the note for SR114. Kaplan's performance is the first part of the evening's program, and Mallach's performance is part two of the program. The tape is edited and/or spliced.
      Scope and content: Venue: Ezra Stiles College, Yale University. Live performance by Alan Mallach. Continued from SR117, followed by Mallach's performance of Gottshalk's "Le Banjo, Op. 15" (listed in the program as Op. 5). His performance is followed by Dave Kaplan, who plays guitar (starting about 00:10:35). He talks about folk music, and performs various songs. Original ID number: S-10.
    - Undergraduate Arts Festival, Ezra Stiles Concert. Part I: The New Folk Music - Dave Kaplan; Part II: Piano Recital - Allan Mallach (four tapes), February 27, 1964, AFC 2016/055: SR117; RXK 4300; 1 sound tape reel (acetate, 00:32:27): analog, 7 1/2 ips; half track, stereo; 7 in.; Mallach studied at Yale University. See the note for SR114.
      Scope and content: Venue: Ezra Stiles College, Yale University. Alan Mallach plays solo piano, performing music of the Romantic period: "Papillons, Op. 2" (Schumann), "Sonata in A Major, Op. 120" (Schubert), and "Concert Paraphrase on a Strauss Waltz" (Schuytt). The recording ends abruptly. Original ID number: S-11.
    - Undergraduate Arts Festival, Ezra Stiles Concert. Part I: The New Folk Music - Dave Kaplan; Part II: Piano Recital - Allan Mallach (four tapes), February 27, 1964, AFC 2016/055: SR118; RXK 4301; 1 sound tape reel (acetate, 00:17:30): analog, 7 1/2 ips; half track, stereo; 7 in.; See the note for SR114.
      Scope and content: Venue: Ezra Stiles College, Yale University. Grand finale: The Battle of Prague (William Terry, piano), with Alan Mallach conducting The Ezra Stiles Percussion Ensemble. Original ID number: S-12.
    - Ulysses G. Wall, May 30, 1964, AFC 2016/055: SR159; RXK 4342; 1 sound tape reel (acetate, 00:50:00): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, stereo; 7 in.; Wall was a student at Southern Connecticut State College, and was in the choir in 1964. He was the member of a group called "Ulysses Wall and Berry," also in 1964.
      Scope and content: A small jazz combo performs standards; Wall is the singer. The group is described in the documentation as "Ulysses Wall with trio." Venue: Exit Coffeehouse. Original ID number: S-25.
    - Doc Watson, #1, March 12, 1965, AFC 2016/055: SR160; RXK 4343; 1 sound tape reel (acetate, 00:43:36): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, stereo; 7 in.; The concert was presented by Indian Neck Folk Music [sic], and held at 100 Art Gallery.
      Scope and content: Continued on SR161. Original ID number: S-42.
    - Doc Watson, #2, March 12, 1965, AFC 2016/055: SR161; RXK 4344; 1 sound tape reel (acetate, 00:44:43): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, stereo; 7 in.; See the archivist's note for SR160.
      Scope and content: Continued from SR160; continued on SR162. Original ID number: S-43. Original ID number note: the reel is labeled S-77.
    - Doc Watson, #3, March 12, 1965, AFC 2016/055: SR162; RXK 4345; 1 sound tape reel (acetate, 00:32:00): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, stereo; 7 in.; See the archivist's note for SR160.
      Scope and content: Continued from SR161. Original ID number: S-44. Original ID number note: the reel is labeled S-42, and the box back is labeled S-41.
    - Andy Woolf, March 30, 1964, AFC 2016/055: SR163; RXK 4346; 1 sound tape reel (acetate, 00:28:00): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, stereo; 7 in.; From 00:22:13 to the end of the file, the audio consists of sine wave tones of varying frequencies. There is no music or any other kind of content past this point. It is included for completeness sake.
      Scope and content: Woolf plays various instruments and songs. The recording includes both vocal and instrumental works. This is a studio recording, with expected pauses and restarts. Original ID number: S-41.
    - Andy Woolf, December 1968, AFC 2016/055: SR164; RXK 4347; 1 sound tape reel (acetate and polyester, 00:27:03): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, stereo; 7 in.; The very beginning and end of the recording includes previously recorded content unrelated to Andy Woolf's recording.
      Scope and content: Woolf describes this on the recording as a test recording. See note for SR163.